Wyatt from Castle Island here and this episode marked the second in our series on stablecoins in DeFi.
Today, I was joined by Hannah and Justin, founders of asymmetry finance, which builds unique stablecoin
offerings in DeFi. Without further ado, I hope you enjoy our conversation.
to make a particular investment or follow a particular strategy, but only as an expression of
their personal opinion. This podcast is for informational purposes only.
Justin, Hannah from asymmetry finance, thanks for joining our podcast. We're going to talk about
stablecoins in DeFi today, which I'm excited for, but would love to get some personal introductions,
if you don't mind, before we get started. I'm Hannah Jojo and I come from a traditional
background actually in finance and risk analysis. I started out my career as an actuary. Actuaries
create risk models and try to find and moderate different risk and systems. I did that for a while.
I was there for a few years working at pension funds, health insurance companies, etc. and
realized I was just maximizing profits for these massive industries. Didn't want to keep doing
that forever. I had always been doing crypto and DeFi on the side, learning about it as I was
studying math. It was just fascinating. It was really starting to take off and we were starting
to see the derivatives products in crypto, all these things that I was classically trained in
up here in crypto and on blockchains. When that really started to boom, I jumped over,
started working in crypto full-time and I've worked at a non-profit in crypto as well as
some DeFi startups and the largest name, Genesis Global Trading, where I was working on their
DeFi portfolio to deploy it to actually things like exactly what was built at asymmetry,
more risk-off ways of getting higher yield on your assets, which we can get into. That's my
background. My background, I started off as a software engineer right out of school. I did it
for AT&T for a Fortune 10 company and then COVID hit and everyone got sent home. The game really
changed quickly after that. I went and helped build a cybersecurity startup in Colorado that was
acquired and then went to go work full-time in crypto, went to go work for ShapeShift
and Eric Voorhees helped transition them from a centralized company into a DAO and really
learned what the process looks like to try and create a flat organization that is managed on
Discord, which is, as you can imagine, comes with some growing pains. I left ShapeShift,
served as head of product for Silo Finance, building isolated lending markets,
learned a lot about obviously how to go to market and how to build frankly good lending
markets there. They've had a lot of success, especially recently on Sonic, which is super
stoked to see and then had an idea for asymmetry and Hannah and I put our heads together and
the rest is history that leads us here. That was almost two, three years ago now. It has been a
rollercoaster, a windy road to get to where we are and really excited to kind of dig into some of
it and chat further. It's been fun. You guys are a flagship case of came from traditional finance,
from traditional software and saw the appeal of crypto and took the pill. I'm excited to hear
about asymmetry. Hannah, I'm curious before we hop into that how you look at the migration of
assessing risk and looking at risk in traditional finance to crypto. There's obviously a lot when
it comes to the intersection of crypto and risk and curious for any views you have or experiences
there. The reason why I migrated over to crypto, I feel like is there weren't a lot of actuaries
here and there is so much risk to measure. We know it's not a riskless space. There's plenty of it,
which is why yield is so high because those are inversely correlated. Higher yield, higher risk,
lower yield, lower risk, et cetera. Coming into crypto and seeing some of the insane yields,
obviously a lot of those carry a lot of risk, which many people have found out the hard way,
but I do think we actually need more professionals like actuaries in the space.
So, Genesis, when they hired me, they were looking for someone who had that risk background
because they had about a billion dollars that they were looking to deploy into different
eye yield products. Eye yield, not meaning the 10,000% APY that some of us are familiar with
in the good old days, but rather things like what we've built at Asymmetry, which is a stable coin
yield somewhere between 10 and 20% APY. Before I joined their team, they deployed a few hundred
million dollars to anchor protocol in UST. I began working there, submitted a risk report saying,
guys, you got to pull this. It's not safe. It is not the same as getting 20% on, say,
SDI or something, SDI with a lending off, something like that.
And they were going to deploy a few hundred million more to UST. I actually got them to
unwind that, so saved them quite a bit there because all of this happened a few weeks before
the big collapse. Just things like that, where sometimes we see these yield numbers and they're
very tempting, but you do need someone to actually understand the risks, explain them
to the public or private. In that case, it was private, but we need people in this space who
are making these risks known. At Asymmetry, we said, let's build high yield products,
but we're not going to shoot for the highest yields, no crazy yield of a few thousand percent
or anything like that, no yield that purely comes from our governance token boosting it up.
Let's build products that have sustainable yields without the risk of a death spiral.
And luckily, it was a hard lesson to learn, but a lot of the market now understands more
of those risks after seeing UST really unwind. And there is still a huge need for products like
that, so that's what we're working on. Your journey into crypto where you came from a risk
background and saw a lack of risk analysis at the time reminds me of some of the high-frequency
traders and market makers early on who might have been philosophically aligned with crypto,
but they really mostly saw just an industry that was sorely lacking these systems in an
efficient markets and plug that hole. You dove into it a little bit, but tell us more about
asymmetry finance and the products you guys are offering today and what your inspirations are.
If you think of asymmetry, the products we're building are these higher yield products.
People in crypto do want yield. If there's no secret there, people want yield. We have a few
products in the convex ecosystem. If you have convex, we're the best place to wrap it,
where it can be most liquid and highest yield, which is a really fun problem to solve. You
normally have to choose one, but the products coming out in the future, I would say, are more
our flagship and their high yield synthetic dollars. We eliminate that downside price pressure risk
mostly by having it be a stablecoin. Then you can mint this stablecoin against assets that are
pretty safe, assets most people know. You can look at SDI already that has some yield baked in,
and then you can borrow against it and increase your yield there. Also, wrapped bitcoin,
some other bitcoin assets. Really, we're just trying to keep it to the safest assets.
You can get more information on all of them on our site, but we're building these high yield
products that people can basically hold as passively as possible and not see their wealth
eroded over time, because we've seen this in parts of the world with hyperinflation.
Argentina, tricky. It's a huge issue if people are holding their life savings,
and they did nothing wrong, and they want it eroded in a year or two because of some
bad at government decisions that are completely out of their control. We're trying to build
passive assets, and Justin will say this, but we also try to make them so easy that your mom
can use it. Really easy interface to use. High yield, relatively risk off assets is what we build.
You guys are building yield products around, say, cornerstone assets, things like convex and
curve, and some larger DeFi assets, as well as these stable coins that you guys are creating
from a functional perspective. Yeah, we've had a long road, so we started a few years ago,
and our first product was actually an index fund for different state-to-eath products,
which would have been really cool, but we built it too early.
Why did you build that in the first place? That was another risk pipe. It was earlier days,
so some of these contracts weren't as proven, and so much money was flowing into e-staking,
and Lido almost had voting majority of ETH, and we said, that's a huge risk to the ecosystem,
and what if their code's bad? We said, we'll offer people a basket of all these assets,
and we took the sixth largest staking products for ETH, and then people could in one click
get access to all of them, and we were just a little bit too early. That's where we started,
though, two and a half years ago, with really the same 14. I'd say in those two and a half years,
we really just learned more easily how to reach the markets they were trying to work with and
attract, and then we've built better and better products that do appeal to the masses, especially
with these high-yield stablecoins, which I think almost everyone would appreciate access to if it
was easy enough for them. I'm bouncing around a little bit, but in that vein, do you think you
get a basket of stablecoins, which becomes the preferred stablecoin, and then maybe a basket
of basket of stablecoins? Do we create traditional fund structures here? I think we could. I think
especially when you look at huge whales, treasuries, et cetera, if you are a startup and you have a
treasury, you want that to be as safe as possible, or if you're a large institution and you have a
treasury, you lose your treasury, you lose everything. Putting it all into one stablecoin or one asset
probably doesn't make a lot of sense. We've seen catastrophic events happen. The USDC-USDT
DPEG a few years ago was just terrifying. It was the two largest stablecoins, really, and they were
DPEG-ing, and no one knew where the floor would be. USD was a stablecoin, and that completely
crashed. I think, one, it's best to understand them, but two, it is best to diversify a little bit,
and also include some decentralized stablecoins in your portfolio. Die as die because those
have performed the best in historical DPEG events.
Yeah, it's a crazy thing, but it's completely true. My colleague, Nick, recently has been talking
a bit about Silvergate and the banking crisis, and you get these periods of traditional finance
contagion. At that point, it can be better to own at least some of these decentralized stablecoins
to your point. From your guys' experience, if someone comes to asymmetry and they have convex,
they're using the protocol to earn yield on their convex, or they have USDC, they're using it to earn
interest on their USDC, does the convex user want yield in convex, and does the USDC person want
yield in USDC? Is the yield denominated as the same in the underlying in all these scenarios, or
how do these products function, and what do people want?
There's two avenues here. On the convex side, as Hannah said, it's called FCVX, but we consider it
to be the best convex wrapper, most liquid wrapper, as well as the highest yielding.
People in the convex ecosystem, it's a really, really powerful ecosystem, and convex throughout
the entire Bayer has paid 20, 25 or so percent APY on convex denominated in convex through this whole
incentive emission, but really bribe and incentive mechanism that they have there. It's been really,
really powerful and proven over a number of years to work really well. Those users who own the convex,
they want yield denominated in more convex. I think there are probably some that harvest their yield
on a bi-weekly basis, sell it into dollars and use that to stay alive, pay the rent,
re-expenses, whatever. That's really meant for a more specific ecosystem, power users who are deep
in this curved convex space. On the other side, there's USDAF and the stables that we're building,
which are really more designed for a user who is seeking to borrow against and use assets they
already own in a more capital-efficient way, yet still fully decentralized. You take your STI,
you take your RAP Bitcoin, you bring it to the protocol, you're able to borrow against it,
set your own interest rates completely permissionlessly, so they'll be able to move with market
dynamics up and down, high interest rate, low interest rate environment doesn't matter. The
system can adjust to it because it's completely market set, completely up to the user, borrow
against it, whatever rate you want, fixed rate, into perpetuity, and then set your LTV, and boom,
you're off to races. Of course, there's a staked version of the stablecoins that will allow users
to have a yield-bearing option as well. I think those will be pretty popular. Then there's a
bunch of vault infrastructure and other pieces we're building on top of it, but I'll leave it
there. There's a couple different layers as we think of it. Looking at those products, people
who use crypto often, I would say those who don't aside, are probably familiar with USDE and you
have Resolve, and you have Usual, and you have USDM, and you have all these different product
offerings. What's the message you guys are trying to convey with USDAF, and how would you orient that
among the landscape of offerings in DeFi? One thing that's really missing at this moment in time
is fixed rate borrowing into perpetuity. A lot of these stablecoins that currently exist,
you can mint them out of other assets, or you have to just go maybe purchase them,
or the minted by a centralized entity, and you buy them from a DEX or something like that,
but there's nowhere out there at the moment that allows users to bring
some of the largest assets in DeFi, bring them to a protocol, and borrow against them
with a fixed rate into perpetuity without any slippage, without any caveats involved in that
process. And I think that's a really big game-changing moment. We're building on top of
Liquidity B2, which Asymmetry has a license to do. They've built awesome tech and candidly
think that this is going to shake up the lending environment a little bit. The other piece to
that is that a lot of these stablecoins are not fully immutable, fully permissionless,
fully decentralized, and have 100% independent oracles. USDAF has all of them, so all of the
oracles are fully independent, built with Chainlink, and then the protocol itself is
completely immutable, completely permissionless. The team has no ability to change it when talking
to larger institutional players. Oracles are 100% independent. There's no risk of having to trust
a small team that you don't know not to upgrade the code and essentially steal the money,
which is inherently a risk, unfortunately, in this space. Is it likely? I don't think so.
I'm not saying that about other teams at all. But if there's not even a possibility of that
happening, if it literally cannot happen physically impossible, it adds another checkmark
to that. When we talk to some larger institutions or whales and they say, well, look, then I feel
really comfortable allocating into this because I know that even in a worst case scenario, no one
can take hold of this thing and turn it into being used for something it wasn't meant to be. So,
to recap, fixed rate lending on user set interest rates, and then this fully permissionless DeFi
first wave that I think is gone by the wayside a little bit with some of these C5 DeFi plays
really strongly principle values of DeFi coming back and then using the best assets to borrow
against there. There are a lot of reasons why the value might be obvious, but in your view,
why is that fixed rate lending piece valuable or meaningful in the backdrop of crypto today?
One thing we've heard repeatedly from larger users is that if they're going to structure a trade,
they need to have a fixed cost of capital. They need to know that right off the bat.
And so when you allocate into one of the current lending protocols, Aave, Compound, whatever,
you are subject to a variable interest rate. Can you give a specific use case here?
We were talking with a fund and they were saying that they're trying to essentially
arb and play this game of taking advantage of borrowing in USDC and then going and purchasing
treasuries. Just a very simple arb. And what's their collateral?
Dollars, I guess, to start, but then they're pulling it over.
They're basically just purchasing bonds on one end, at least just from when we heard that it
wasn't clear if they were borrowing against something to get those dollars, but they were just
buying, say, T-bills, bonds, comparing that to kind of a chain yield.
And in bear markets, you find that to pick on Aave, because they're the biggest,
the rate that you get on supplying USDC, for example, is under your T-bill rate, at least
it has been this last year, but you're taking on smart contract risk and custody risk and everything
in order to do that, where you could go get, I'll call it totally risk-free yield with T-bills.
There's an arbitrage there, I would say, on the flip side. In a bull market, if you're supplying
USDC, great, you might get massive yield, but someone's borrowing it on the other side to pay
that yield. They deposited, and they're like, all right, we're going to borrow at 4% or something,
and now in a bull market, it's 17%. And you're like, okay, well, whatever trade I was doing,
or I wouldn't go pay it off a house, it doesn't matter anymore. It's not profitable,
I'm underwater, and that fixed cost of capital is a big deal.
Yeah, it's efficient markets. To me is what it seems like. If you're a Bitcoin retholder and you
can go borrow some USDC and then earn yield on it, that is above your rate, then you might as well
do that, and it's positive for the market broadly. What user profile is you guys going after with
that in mind? Is this your everyday, your small fish or whale type DeFi users or institutions,
or how do you look at your audience? We're trying to attract everyone. I think many people might
say that about their product. I'm sure any food company is like, we're trying to attract everyone,
but at the end of the day, everyone uses money, and everyone probably wants to earn yield on the
money they're not using. It is pretty simple. In the first few years here, though, definitely,
it's on chain yields, so we're attracting a lot of the power users of DeFi as well as people that
are dabbling. We put a lot of work into making our front end as easy as possible, so easy your mom
could use it, and in the future, we want things to be so easier. Grandma can use it without
knowing she's even using it. That's where the integrations come with traditional payment system
companies. If you have a high yield synthetic dollar, it does make sense for PayPal or Visa to use
that on the back end and give users some of those rewards. If you're on chain, you get all those
rewards. I think this is actually something that if built well and it's proven that it lasts and it
hits a certain size upon which the risk is deemed minimal, then it really can be used on the back
end of financial systems. I think we will see high yield synthetic dollars there. Definitely,
what we're trying to do at asymmetry is poise this to have one of the best chances of being there
eventually. Obviously, those would be the most risk-off versions of the asset, so probably
collateralized by stable coins like Dynastai rather than backed by Bitcoin for the really big
backing payment systems piece, but that is the end goal. Right now, we're trying to attract everyone,
whales, minnows, anyone who has money that they want their yield on, which it turns out is most
of the world. It's a fascinating point you made towards the end there, which is you hit a certain
scale and then continue to attract more users. I think especially in the context of DeFi and
maybe even crypto today where people are trying really hard to get a certain amount of deposits
or TVL, and then it's almost like there's an escape velocity and people say, oh, well,
there are $50 million deposits. I can put my money in now. There's an irony to that in what is
supposed to be a trustless system. First off, I would make the point, how do you look at that
dynamic? Is that something that you guys think about often of, oh, if we can just get to this
amount of deposits, then more people will come or this is the number that we need to get to and
then something else will happen or do you think it's overblown or how do you look at that?
You can count on humans being irrational. As irrational as it is, there are these different
psychological barriers. If you're under a certain barrier, a group of people are not comfortable
with the asset. If you're over it, a new group unlocks. It really is a snowball rolling down a
hill. I think the psychological barriers tend to be $10 million in TVL and then $100 million
and then $1 billion. Once you get into the billions, people start to lose track.
Once you're there, I'd say that's true escape velocity once you pass the $1 billion mark in TVL.
I think the psychological barriers are irrational because if you're at $900 million
in TVL, I don't think people give you a proportional credit if you earn 10% more,
attract 10% more. But they are irrational in that the larger something is, the bigger of a
essentially hacker bounty that is, where if someone is able to find a loophole in that code
and exploit it, that money starts to drain. The more money, it's the larger bounty that
people haven't been able to break into. It does give security in that sense, but I would say
if I could hack very large code bases, $100 million would be about the same as $1 billion
to me. No one can offer him that much money. I think anything beyond say $50 or $100 million
in TVL, that's still quite a big feat to not have your code hacked or broken into. I think
it is rational that we assess some amount of value, but probably not rational how much we assess.
But it is a snowball rolling down a hill because once you pass that $1 billion TVL barrier,
that is a parameter in people's mind and in some people's risk models. The larger
you grow, the more investors you attract because you're unlocking these next groups
of risk tolerance. The larger you get now, you're less risky and you can attract more of
those people and I think it just kind of keeps going. You walk past a restaurant on the street
and there's no one eating in it. You keep walking. Whereas you go to the next restaurant and it's
packed, you're like, yeah, this place has to be good if this many people are eating here.
It's the same concept. It doesn't always play out. That restaurant could be wrong,
though. That restaurant could be bad. You could be eating at Terra restaurant and you get the 20
billion or whatever it is and you check the box, but it doesn't really make a difference. So size
is not everything. I guess this is all I'll say about that. Speaking of restaurants that a lot
of people go to, I wanted to ask you guys about Ethereum switching gears a little bit, which I
think has been the hot button topic for a lot of people in crypto. I think we're seeing this
dynamic where you still have the overwhelming amount of usage that's occurring on the given
venue and we're also seeing an interesting dynamic where there are probably protocols,
which have a lot of usage and their token performance don't quite align, but that can
create certain sentiment in the market. So with that in mind, I'm curious for your perspective
on whether Ethereum remains and will remain the core place to build out products and where crypto
transacts and exists or if there will be a migration there. Wherever the liquidity is,
is where I think the majority of large scale transactions will take place. Like liquidity
is a moat for sure. And if you have the most liquidity in one place, then the largest actors
will continue to transact there because there's the most liquidity and it's a self-fulfilling
prophecy. Can that change or is that set? That might change. It certainly has a hell of a head
start and a lead on it, but I think that could change. We think about it and we're very bullish on
this concept of the fat app thesis that a lot of this L1 premium across the board will start to
disappear and that it really is more so about the apps that exist across multiple chains rather than
the chain itself. Apps must go multi-chain and find users across them and then it's really more so
true long-term adoption. Looks like a Venmo style app or whatever where people are using crypto
rails, but they don't really know it and it doesn't matter what chain they're on. They're just using
the asymmetry app. Whether it's ETH based or whatever else based, it doesn't really matter to
them because it's all about the app and the distribution at the end of the day. But liquidity
is a moat from a structural perspective. But to your point, I think it could change. We'll see,
but it just depends on, I mean, you've seen obviously ETH's performance against BTC since
the merge. It's then pretty poor. So maybe there's something there of in hindsight, we look back in
Roman Empire, we say, oh, that was the day where it kind of all started to fall apart, but everyone
still told themselves, oh, we're still the greatest empire for the 20 years. Yeah, hundreds of years
later. Maybe that was the moment. Maybe it's not. I don't know. We still build on ETH. I'm a big
believer that ETH is an incredible ecosystem. And of course, wherever the liquidity is,
is a massive driver of building at its core beyond all else.
I personally have a view that Bitcoin probably won't transact on Bitcoin's main chain eventually
in the sense that it will sit and just be denominated elsewhere, almost like a safe in a bank.
The money stays there while people trade claims to it. And I wonder if we go a similar direction
with Ethereum, which is to say that most of the liquidity in TVL is on Ethereum. But as these cross
chain settlement and liquidity systems get better, that you just have representation of these assets
moving across other chains or, dare I say, even saying moving off chain with claims to on-chain
assets. It's an interesting concept, especially claims to on-chain assets. You look at the blow-ups
that have happened. DeFi performed before CeFi did. You had to repay your maker loans
before you could go haggle with whoever these funds got loans from in the CeFi world. So,
from a transparency perspective, I think that works really well.
When it works really well, I'll say for high-yield stablecoins, this is how we can onboard the next
group of people that don't even know how to use these blockchain systems, but they can benefit
from the technology that's being built with a portion of savings in it. I think it is a logical
next step for the industry, and it would really unlock a lot for it as well.
Did you guys see the Galaxy data recently speaking of lending that showed how much
DeFi lending has surged and CeFi lending is a fraction of what it was? I'm asking Hannah,
who worked at Genesis this question, I guess, I realize as I speak, but it was fascinating data.
It's fascinating, and going to Justin's point, it makes sense on-chain lending,
it can't fail because the code will execute, and there's certain parameters as an actuary.
It's amazing to have programmable money with parameters that you can count on, because when
I worked at Genesis, and FTX collapsed, and we were undergoing a lot of counterparty risk.
Basically, it was a bit shocking to me that I found out that most of the traditional finance
world, if someone defaults on their loan, you call them. In your meeting, you're like,
yeah, they're on vacation right now, but they say they're good for it, so we'll give them a few days.
I didn't really realize that. I was a little bit shocked because I was actually first exposed
to loans at DeFi, before I saw the back end of CeFi loans. It was pretty shocking that it was
really a vouching system, and very verbally-based, what people said and not just did they pay or not.
I think that on-chain loans are definitely an innovation that will begin to take precedence
in finance, because now we do have programmable money that can execute on these things with
zero human interaction, which is a really big step for things like loans.
The other day, I was looking at some of the asset attestations, particularly before you had
some of these meltdowns, where you would just get a letter from a funder in exchange that says,
we have this much Bitcoin, period signed. It's incredible. Then the other day, I also saw,
have you guys seen what AI can do with these receipts? You can probably have GPT do this,
but you can create a crumpled receipt with the name of a restaurant and expenses and look so
incredibly real. It reminds you why having money on-chain, you can see every step of the transaction
is so valuable. I remember actually, Justin, this was back around the time that we met,
which for other people was about four or five years ago. Justin and I both wrote pieces for
our family and friends explaining crypto concepts and macroecon and how crypto was involved.
We were just trying to pill everyone. I remember I was doing a deep dive on all the stable coins.
I found out that USDC and USDT, they were audited, but the auditing companies back then said,
we give this, what was the terminology? I don't remember the exact words, but it was basically
like we're mildly sure about this. Then they give the report. The first sentence was, we're not really
that sure, but here's what we're saying to express it. It was not certainly. After USDT
underwent a lot of scrutiny, their auditing has gotten much better in the recent years,
but that just goes to show these paper attestations are quite funny. We will definitely find better
ways of validating data than paper, especially in that age of AI. I think people are going to
have to move faster on that than they realize. That is a really good point, Wyatt.
Yeah, and a funny way to probably be the exploits, which drive people to move faster as it always is.
To this point about a lot of the transitions we're seeing, what is the world that you guys
hope to see and maybe that asymmetry falls in line with when it comes to future finance,
direction of DeFi, crypto? What do you hope to see and what are your predictions?
One of the large reasons why I got into crypto, I mentioned I worked here at a nonprofit,
and that was actually my first job I took into space. It was Giveth, which is a nonprofit focused
on basically charity payments. They would let people donate or raise money permissionlessly
and then send the money and pay the gas. It was actually a free way of fundraising,
unlike GoFundMe, which takes crazy fees. What a lot of people started using this for was actually
cross-border payments for migrant workers or people sending money back home,
and that was always a use case that I thought was fascinating because if you look at Western Union,
if you're sending money to Syria, you actually lose more than 50% of the value
through Western Union by the time it arrives. Argentina, you lose about 10% to 15% depending
how much you're sending. These are criminal rates. If you work hard and earn money in a country and
you're sending it to your family, that should not be a 50% reduction in value to an intermediary
that doesn't do that much. Sorry, Western Union. But I think that there's two basic human rights,
and it's sending your money securely and also storing it and not seeing the value erode over
time. I really think that in the future, one of the biggest things that crypto can bring to the
world is actually a safe storage of value that doesn't erode and is inflation resistant and
outpaces inflation, hopefully, but at the very least protects against it. Then also,
people should be able to send money across borders without permission
and for close to free. The products we're building are in line with both of those things,
which is why we're here. I don't think you can build something for multiple years that you're
not passionate about. That's why these are great assets that I think much of the world can benefit
from. Maybe we're not the best, but someone will be. I hope we're the best. We're definitely trying
doing everything we can to get there, but at the end of the day, we are contributing to
this ecosystem with fixed rate lending, bringing a big innovation to it that might
appeal to the next group of masses. Those steps need to be made so that these products can
reach everyone globally. Yeah. Hannah said it really well there. I really think that
on-chain assets will eat the world and all or at least the vast majority of stuff will come
on chain at some point. I think that's a beautiful thing for eliminating a lot of the friction
that exists with current financial systems across a bunch of different asset classes,
honestly, not just dollars or bonds or whatever, but even talking about real estate and going
further. Can you tokenize and bring this stuff on chain in a transparent manner?
And just reduced friction, I think, is the biggest use case for it. I think you've seen that
throughout history of a new technology comes in, people are pre-skeptical at first,
and then they realize, wow, this is actually going to make my life way easier and or I can make more
money. Sure enough, everything starts to transition. People thought the internet was a fad. There
were plenty of people who thought Bitcoin was a fad. I think we're to the point now where we are
pretty damn sure it's not a fad and that this trend is going to accelerate. I saw that stablecoins,
this part of that Alex Thorn's Galaxy Research, I think they were doing more volume than Visa or
something along those lines. That's an incredible number that I think went under the radar and what
feels like a little bit of a bear weird uncertainty time. A couple years ago, that would have been
unfathomable and that would have been headline news, screaming across MSNBC, sending to my parents
and everything. I'm like, look, stablecoins are real. This is actually happening. And now it's
just like stablecoins are doing more volume than Visa, whatever. That is a huge deal. And I think
this trend only continues and it then becomes a question of what assets do people want to allocate
to? What assets do they want to borrow against? And can you give them a service that they haven't
necessarily had before, which is where this fixed rate lending impetus and push from the asymmetry
side really comes in, is I'm shocked that it's taken this long to have fixed rate lending into
perpetuity and DeFi. I think it's going to be a massive wave. And I think that one day we'll look
back and we'll go, wow, I can't believe it even took this long. Of course we needed fixed rate
lending because no one in draft buy borrows, floating rates, they just don't. How have we not
had this in DeFi yet? And I think we'll look back and say, wow, I can't believe it took that long,
but glad it's here. And that's really the wave that I think will be a big piece of.
Justin, I'm just going to throw this out there. That Visa chart was a Castle Island chart at
first, but I'll forgive you for it. We'll give credit where credit is due. I know you were out
there crunching the numbers, so I take it back. It was Wyatt. No, I'll credit Nick Carter for that
one. Last thing I wanted to touch on when I have someone here who assesses risk and someone who
looks at the code, what keeps you up at night and what are your concerns, if any? I think for me,
I'll start in the present moment and then kind of go broader. But in the present moment,
my biggest fear is just we are losing interested market participants because everything is too
difficult to use. And it's something that often gets very overlooked because you, me, Justin,
we've put in the time. We know how to use wallets. We know how to use bridges. I have definitely
onboarded a lot of friends to crypto and through their eyes, I've seen it is still really bad
of an onboarding process. And it's scary because if you make a mistake, you lose your money.
That's that white knuckle experience. I think that in the near term, that is the number one
thing we need to work on, even though most of the builders in the space, Justin and I included,
are so obsessed with the tech. But more builders in the space need to focus on the actual experience
and make it as easy as possible. And that's something that we have really prioritized.
So people when they're within our DAP, everything's one or two click access. We explain the risks
and people can make informed decisions. And kind of the longer term, gosh, at this point,
honestly, most of my worry centers around like meme coin ecosystem, I think it will die a little
bit. But I think that it does a lot of negative for our industry in terms of reputation, in terms
of being considered an online casino. With time, I think that's something that will go away.
But it does lack a lot of checks and balances. And there's just a lot of speculation, which is fine
if you acknowledge that it's an online casino. But if it's people are bringing their hard earned
money, and they're taking it to meme coins, rather than something like USDAF, which is a stable coin
that earns high yield, and it's relatively safe compared to meme coins, but they're bringing
hard earned money, they might not have that much of it. And then they're losing it in a meme coin
pump and dump. I think that's really unfortunate. And we'll see a lot of people burned that way
because they're told that they have to buy this coin. That just comes down to people being informed
again about really what they're getting into. I encourage all other protocols to be very
transparent about the risks of the protocol with users, they can make informed decisions,
because some people will think the risk is worth it, and others won't. But that's what we're doing
at ASM, making everything as clear as possible, answering all the questions from the community
when I encourage other protocols to do that too, so that we can really scale.
The only thing that really scares me at this point is some weird black swan that we don't even know
about an FTX 2.0, something along those lines. I think DeFi has gotten a lot better post TerraLuna.
Things are transparent. And I think there's a lot less death spiral risk than there was then.
A lot more of these mechanics have been fleshed out. And that's part of a growing ecosystem,
like you have these growing pains. Any birth of a new financial market is going to have everyone
from legitimate builders to scammers and everyone in between. It's kind of speed running this
capital formation process, which is both headline grabbing at times and not great, but also
long term, really, really healthy. You have to kind of flesh a lot of this crap out
in order to find what sticks around long term. My fear is that there's another
black swan lurking around the corner in some way, shape, or form that we just don't know about yet.
We haven't seen it yet. And that puts a big dent in things, but you can't worry about something
that you don't know that even exists. So for us, it's keep our heads down, build, try and build
the right way as transparent as possible and be as close to the community as possible, build
in accordance with our principles and try and carry, I think, that torch of the decentralization,
immutability, trying to do things in the right way to make sure that we can sleep at night.
So I think that's a big piece of the dose that we try to build with. And then it's just
go to market, try and get these products in the hand of people that want to use them,
need to use them, and everyone in between. Well, we'll leave it there. For anyone listening,
go check out asymmetry finance. Hannah and Justin, thanks for coming on. Hopefully,
we can do it again at some point. Thanks for having us. Thanks for listening to another episode
of On the Brink with Castle Island. To find out more about Castle Island, visit castleisland.vc.
To listen to all of our podcast episodes, please go to on the brink-podcast.com
or just click on the tab in our website. Thanks for listening.